

ANKIT SRIVASTAV

PRODUCT TECHNICAL CONTENT WRITER

PERSONAL PROFILE

Strong technical writer with 5+ years of experience writing end-user documentation for high-end SAAS based platforms and services. Seeking to grow brand loyalty and technical knowledge base with global companies.

Award-winning writer with hands-on experience in technical writing tools and methodologies. Advance programming and algorithm building suite comes as the added advantage.

SKILLS

Technical:

DITA XML
SQL & Neo4j
CMS, CCMS & DMS
Java (Spring boot and Microservices)
Android & iOS Development
HTML, CSS, Javascript
GIT & DevOps
Testing & QA

Non Technical:

Search Engine Optimization Bitbucket, GCP Wordpress Jira, Confluence

CONTACT INFORMATION

P Delhi, India

(+91) 7087810182

ankitsrivastav1995@gmail.com

in linkedin.com/in/ankitsrivastav1995

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Technical Content Writer

3SC Solution Pvt. Ltd. (Aug 2022 - Now)

- Part of product documentation and marketing team
- Worked on content creation as well as SAAS documentation
- Created technical blogsband articles on technical topics
- Assisted on SAAS Product SCAI and worked on sustainability

Technical Content Writer

HeadSpin Pvt. Ltd. (Sep 2021 - July 2022)

- Part of business as well as technical team
- Assisted in problem solving and brainstorming solutions to existing concerns
- Worked on technical content creation as well as documentation
- Created guides on various languages and testing platforms
- Wrote integration documents for the platform

Technical Writer - APAC

Milestone Technologies (July 2021 - Sep 2021)

- 3 Months Contract
- Worked with Amneal and Uber as clients
- Written SOPs and Help Desk Documentations from scratch

Technical Lead - Documentation

Tickle (Aug 2017 - June 2021)

- Worked on both in-house and client products
- Lead a team of 21 writers, both local and international
- Worked on API Documentation, User Guide, and Manuals

EDUCATIONAL HISTORY

Punjab Technical University

Bachelor in Technology, Computer Science 7.4 CGPA

Ambedkar Institute of Technology

Diploma, Computer Engineering 7.3 CGPA

PROJECTS

SCAI (2023)

Developed all web content and documentation for SCAI Technologies Used: Nodejs, Neo4j, DITA, XML, AWS Tools Used: Ms Visio, Draw.io, Postman, Robohelp, Adobe AEM

EVE Platform (2022)

Developed API docs for Extraction & Verification (EVE) Platform Technologies Used: Nodejs, Neo4j, DITA, XML, AWS Tools Used: Ms Visio, Draw.io, Postman, Robohelp, Adobe AEM

Quark (2021)

Created all web documentation for all 6 Quark Author Products Technologies Used: DITA, XML, JS, HTML, CSS Tools Used: Ms Visio, Document360, Snagit, Office 365

CERTIFICATIONS

- IBM Certification for Java Development
- · Udemy Certification for Technical Writing
- · Google Certification for Marketing, Sales, and Analytics